okay now I'm moving on to the deadlift
and one thing I forgot to talk about
with a spot but it applies above the
squad the damage is breathing I see a
lot of people that don't know how to
breathe correctly you want to take a
deep breath about 70% of course I don't
know the exact percentage but that's
that's what I read in the literature but
you don't go too deep as possible but
you get a deep breath and then you hold
it so and I did it I hold that breath
till I passed my sticky point and then
breathe out now if just still throws up
top you don't want to trying to say
breathe out breathe out if you're just
going heavy you don't breathe out until
after your sticking point because you
you lose your stability or
intra-abdominal pressure goes down
you're into thoracic pressure goes down
so you want to keep that it's a
protective excess gonna let you lift
more weights and it protects you so
breathe in deep about 70% and hold it
till after your sequel if you're repping
out you might be able to breathe more
smoothly but when going heavy deep
breath after my Stevie point all right
so now common problems with the deadlift
all right here's what I see conv
problems number one people will try and
mimic their squat I see them using too
wide of a stance
they'll try and be like this and then
they'll go grab it like this if your
arms are right in front of your knees
then you're having to lean forward more
that's not good the arms need to go
either between the knees or out 70 so if
you're doing a conventional deadlift
the arms going right outside the knees
like this if you're doing a sumo
deadlift then the arms would go inside
the knees so see that these are here or
here so most people do credential notice
they need to have a little bit narrower
stance in the
we use now another common problem is
where they like it with the bar a lot of
people will join lineup really far away
from the bar like like this like this
far away from the bar and then try and
run and they try and squat it like this
and I'm drunk like that that is not a
good debit that is you're trying to make
it look like a squat it's not good form
you will never get strong that way when
you do a debit the hips stay higher it's
not a squat all right if you are
squatting the parallel your form might
look like this but your demo look like
this okay squat dead let's see how the
hips are I so this is people argue about
where where to line up something will
say one inch from the shin so we will
say two inches from machine some people
say through the mid foot some people
recommend getting a little bit closer
and trying to sit back more some people
say a little bit farther away and then
try and bend forward a little more
without all depends on the lifter but in
general you know two inches from the bar
and then come down and try and keep your
hips high while keeping your chest up so
one thing I use to tell people look in
the mirror you should be able to read
your shirt that doesn't mean stay like
that because we'll talk about the neck
later but if I come down and I going to
tell it like this my upper back is going
I can't read my sugar meter so we must
show them here I've got to get to right
here all right now so this would get
good position see all my hips are high
so get your shins close to the bar your
stance narrower it is not a squat get
your hips higher and make sure you can
read your shouldn't hear the
lastly I want to say is don't when
you're looking in the mirror you're kind
of overextending your neck so your
cervical spine so you really want to
tuck your chin and kind of look down
that's the save this way so I'll show
you what that looks like so I am going
together I can see my shift in there
good form now the last thing I do it
tuck my chin and look down alright
another problem is so we'll do a good
demo concentric ly and then eccentric ly
their form falls apart and that's
because a lot of times people lift up
and then just drop the way they're used
to Olympic lifting or or they don't
really think the eccentric is important
the eccentric face should look exactly
like a concentric tree so I watch people
and they'll you know they'll give a good
debit and then from here we'll go like
that no these are mirror images of one
another
this exact same okay so trying to think
I'm trying to end guy and hit all the
major points but it just takes practice
and some people don't have the mobility
right off the bat to do adela usually
their hamstrings are too stiff
so if they were if it's you like someone
on their back and their hamstring stops
here you know their their their hip
flexion mobility string like hip flexion
with really sucks here they probably
can't do a deadlift you need to be able
to come up you know close to a right
angle not quite but in order to be a
good doctor you have to have good
hamstring flexibility this is flexible
answers if they don't this is what
happens they go to bend down hamstring
flexibility run down here the only other
way to get there is to just round over
the back like that so if you have for
entry flexibility you're gonna round in
the depth in that case start people off
out of the rack okay problem with rifles
I see is people will lie on a far away
and try and squat it up like this not
what your dead look looks like when you
do a dump here right here this is what
you look like I'm not like this okay so
the raffle should look like that part of
the devil so why not close and you know
like lean over the bar it's almost like
it's like a semi straight leg debit or a
partial straight leg damn it and you
come down most be modded a hamstring
flexibility this okay
so you don't have good hamstring
flexibility you can still provide a
training effect by doing rifles work on
increasing your hamstring flexibility
and then eventually move down and you
start doing the full rate debit hope you
found these videos useful thanks a lot